Medical doctor
AI engineer
Same person
so now I get annoyed by two
industries instead of one I'm Kaeyomerz
Every clinic day throws up a puzzle
a patient who won't respond to a
first-line drug
a lab value that doesn't fit
Turning that spark into a testable experiment
takes weeks of reading
and a favour from a computational
biologist
So most sparks just die on the
whiteboard
And this is where TransBench comes in
Here's what it actually does
It takes that one plain sentence and
breaks it into biological angles
It writes hypotheses
you could prove wrong
then goes to the real literature
PubMed and Europe PMC
and grounds every one in papers you
can actually open If a citation won't
resolve it's dropped
Eight agents and three rigor gates wired
together with LangGraph
it demotes textbook facts
and when nothing clears the bar it
ships nothing
Opus writes the hypotheses
and designs the experiment
Sonnet decomposes
and checks novelty
Haiku grades
and assembles the brief
Here's the fun part
I barely wrote a line of it
by hand
I tunnelled into a bare Linux server
from VS Code
and let the Claude command line do
the building
agents that read the real docs
a scanner that guards every push
hooks that won't let me ship a
mess
And when I was stuck on the
ward
I kept it going from my phone
on breaks
Things that would've meant days of learning
and hours of building I did in
minutes
And any scientist
or doctor can run it too
one copy-paste into Claude Code no engineering
It even replays
byte-identical
so the results are yours to reproduce
Watch
I paste a plain observation
It breaks the case into angles
proposes hypotheses
tied to real clickable papers
and when the evidence isn't there it
says so and ships nothing
The guardrails I set up wouldn't budge
The brief hands me a ready-made prompt
I drop it into Claude Science
it pulls a real public single-cell dataset
like the Gladstone T-cell data and it
can pull others whenever the question calls
for it It runs the analysis
and draws the figures
A sentence at the bedside
to a grounded hypothesis
to a figure
the next step is a pipette
not another meeting
And you can run it yourself
same inputs
same figure every time
Today it's one run at a time
Next text it an observation from WhatsApp
like you'd text a colleague
It strips patient identifiers before a word
is stored
It remembers
every brief
so when new evidence lands
it pings you that hunch you had
It's grounded now
One confession
this video was planned and edited by
Claude Code too
I mostly just told Claude how I
was feeling
None of this fits into a weekend
without the Max plan
so thank you One clinician
one command line and a model that
kept me honest
This is just a preview
the whole thing's documented on GitHub
If you're wondering what I'd build with
a team around me instead of a
terminal
so am I